Christian König

Biodiversity data scientist and ecological modeler

Profile

I'm a biodiversity data scientist and ecological modeler who seeks new challenges outside academia. During my scientific career, I acquired in-depth knowledge in areas ranging from R programming, statistical modeling, database development to independent problem solving and effective communication. I successfully concluded projects as diverse as predicting the geographical origin of island species, making conceptual contributions to biodiversity data integration, and developing an interactive shiny web application to improve documentation of ecological models. I am also a passionate learner, which is reflected by the extracurricular courses I took to strengthen my expertise in Python and machine/deep learning.

Experience

Postdoctoral researcher (Mar 2019 - Jul 2021)

Humboldt University of Berlin & University of Potsdam

Shiny application development | Bayesian hierarchical modeling | Predictive ensemble modeling of species invasions | Workshop organization and presentation

Doctoral researcher (Mar 2015 - Feb 2019)

Georg-August University of Göttingen

Biodiversity data ETL and database development | Global geospatial analyses | Teaching and supervision

Education

Georg-August University of Göttingen

Macroecology and Biodiversity data science (2015 - 2019) Doctor of sciences (Dr. rer. nat.), predicate: magna cum laude

Georg-August University of Göttingen

Biodiversity, Ecology & Evolution (2012 - 2014) Master of Science (M.Sc.), **final grade: 1.2**

Hochschule für Technik und Wirtschaft Dresden

Environmental monitoring (2008-2012) Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.), **final grade: 1.8**

Extracurricular online courses

 $\underline{6.86x}$ - Machine Learning with Python-From Linear Models to Deep Learning (15 weeks, ~250h online course at MITx on edX)

 $\underline{6.00.2x}$ - Introduction to Computational Thinking and Data Science (9 weeks, ~135h online course at MITx on edX)

<u>6.00.1x</u> - Introduction to Computer Science and Programming using Python (9 weeks, ~135h online course at MITx on edX)

Achievements & Honors

Successful collaborations with diverse groups of international researchers

17 peer-reviewed publications in international academic journals

More than 10 oral presentations at international conferences

Winner of the 2016 visualization award of the German Ecological society



RG





Contact

Address

Nollendorfstr. 24 10777 Berlin

E-mail

chr.koenig@outlook.com

Phone

Python

+49 152 53474680

Technical skills

Statistics & modeling

00000

Machine learning

Data visualization

SOL & Databases

Geospatial analysis

•••••

scikit-learn

R-Shiny

PBS/Slurm

NumPy

Linux

GIS

Git

Bayes

.

ggplot2

Professional skills

CSS/html

English

••••

German

••••

Communication

Problem solving

Creativity

Teamwork